so what would you say to young people
who feel as though they can listen to
hip hop and be Christian mhm I mean
what's what's wrong with it yeah you
know
um I know like God uses different people
in different places right so when I was
uh getting my understanding of uh of
this gospel and of this truth um it's a
you know we were we were so excited
about what we were learning that we were
we said we're going to take the Three
Angels messages and we're going to put
it in our hip-hop music and we will go
into clubs and we will be performing and
we would pull out great controversy
books out of our
backpacks we were like we were like who
wants to know who the man of sin is
throw your hands in the air people throw
their hands in the air and we throw out
great controversy books wow wow and so
you know God used us for where we were
he used us at our you know at our that
level of knowledge that we had and he
uses different people in those different
places and so you know now when you you
know you listen to the lyrics of a lot
of these songs and it's just I mean it's
rock music it's all kinds of different
things and you know I think the more you
you you you try to get the mind of
Christ that's the key thing striving for
the mind of
Christ will show you how how Christ
wants you to walk and so you know like I
said there are different people in
different places but learning that's
what I've learned over my years is being
a Christian sometimes you can point to
things and be like you know you
shouldn't do this or you shouldn't do
that but that's why my passion has
really become studying the Bible because
I think once people learn how to focus
on Christ all the other things you know
that we typically like you know all
those things begin to become
self-evident and so that's where my
passion has become you know really
teaching people how to get into the word
of God and you've even named your system
haven't you what's the name of it it's
called photo
Theology and um the meaning behind that
name is basically the study of God
through the use of pictures and we'll
get into that definition a little bit
more but uh it's interesting because you
know when I became a a Seventh Day
Adventist I I did didn't come in through
an Evangelistic series I didn't um come
in through going to school uh it was I
was you know a friend of a friend of
minees basically asked us a question one
night very interesting he he asked us
what day we think the Sabbath is and
we're all you know like 20 to 30 of us
we're all just hanging out this night
talking and you know all dread locked
down and smoking our marijuana and stuff
and out of the blue this guy that we
never met before just asked us this
question I mean he was a friend of a
friend of a friend of ours but we did
not know him so it was our first time
meeting him that night we were talking
about something I can't remember and he
it was kind of along the lines of
spiritual things and at that time you
know we were just mixing spiritual
things like you know like being kind of
eclectic rappers you know yo man the the
New World Order man they out to get you
yo yo watch out man you know Mark of the
Beast Man watch out for those soap boxes
yo you know so that kind of stuff and um
he asked us what day do we think the
Sabbath is and we were just like that is
a silly question like what do you mean
what day is a Sabbath everyone knows
what day that is it's Sunday and from
that one question in that moment this
guy begins to break down to us Daniel
chapter 2 Daniel chapter 7 and this
whole change that that the Bible said
was going to happen and all these
different things and that really changed
it was that night that everything
changed for us so
um I didn't learn through an
Evangelistic series I basically I didn't
even know the guy was Adventist you know
for a while we were just like there is
no one on the planet that knows the
Bible as good as this guy right and like
couple weeks later we were like hey what
are you he was like I'm a s-day
Adventist what is that never heard of it
before M so we end up going to church
with him for the first time and I share
this in my testimony all the time you
know we went into that church and
imagine like 20 of us walking up into
this little church in in Laurelton
Queens um uh Lebanon it was a Lebanon
7th Day Adventist Church okay and um the
people were just like sh like who is who
are these people walking up into our
church right all like jeans and you know
gum and we we go in there and sit down
and as a pastor is speaking we are like
losing our
minds we're like What yo he just said
that Jesus is the
Lord and and everyone else was sitting
around
like yeah yeah and we were like hold on
hold on
they must not have just heard that the
pastor just said that you have to pay
tithe they must not have heard that
because I've never heard that truth
before tithe
everybody and we would look around like
what is the matter with these people and
we just didn't care we were like we just
lost it like literally everything the P
just said we and so that's where like
you know sometimes people see me preach
and they're like he gets excited when
Hees yeah it it it's not something
that's manufactured like that's how we
came into the church yes and we were
just kind of shocked to look around and
see people
like we're like we're not getting this
and it's been 24 25 years now you know
however long it's been since I've been
since I've been in a church and it is
still the same issue like I don't get it
you understand what I'm saying like how
is it that we are not more excited MH
about the things that God has shown Us
in the scriptures yes and so you know I
this is how photo theology for me
developed because I really didn't know
like I said I didn't go to school to
learn to study how the Bible because I
didn't even know we had Adventist had
schools so I was
learning in a way that God was speaking
to me and I didn't not even realize it
you know cuz I didn't know there is a
system to Bible study and this is I
never had any of that yes so as a hi hop
artist you
know the thing about musicians and you
you probably you know this is that we're
very artistic right music is a very
creative thing it takes a creative mind
to be a musician so in the hip-hop
industry whenever you write Rhymes you
don't want to say what anyone else has
said you don't want to we called it
biting back in the day bite right so you
had to write in a way that was uniquely
your own style mhm and so we would
always be trying to think of how can I
put this in a different way how how can
I see that in a different way that's how
we wrote Our lyrics so when it came to
studying the Bible I didn't necessarily
realize that that's what I was doing but
that's what I was doing right and it
wasn't an intentional thing it was just
like okay I'm looking at these words in
the scripture and I'm like huh man that
word is pretty interesting and I'd see
that word like 200 different ways like
huh
yeah and I just get like wow that that's
powerful yeah
so photo theology is basically what
ended up coming becoming the way that
God taught me how to study the
Bible what was it like when that flip
happened when you found out that the
Sabbath was Saturday the seventh day
Sabbath what was that like it was it was
mind-blowing you know it was um I felt
like I was in a twilight
zone right in a sense it was just like
hold on how can this be true and
remember at this time I don't know that
there's a whole movement called called
adventism so I'm just thinking how can
everyone have this wrong yeah yeah and
then I you know for for a few a little
while I was
like
me and my friends
and this guy are the only ones on the
planet that have this
information and now it is up to
us to let the world
know you know I mean that was just for a
little while and then it was like oh oh
okay there's a whole movement oh
okay isn't it amazing
how many times you don't even know you
have that void you know that something's
missing or maybe you're you're just
going through life and you don't really
realize what's missing till you get it
yeah and then when you get it what an
amazing feeling that is like here you
are just absorbing all of this
information like a sponge and it's so
exciting to you because this is
something really new for you you're in
church and you're hearing all of this
truth and the many times we as members
take things for granted you know you
hear things and you hear sermons and all
and you're you can take it for granted
you can take the truths for granted if
your relationship with the Lord is not
remaining fresh yeah yeah I I'll tell
you I've heard you know before I became
an Adventist as I was growing up as a
young person and getting into college
you know I I would hear different
religious groups Rel you know we had
people come to our campus and you know
speak and stuff like that and I was
always like you know that message sounds
stupid that sounds stupid you know I was
in a sense skeptical of religion okay I
was like you know I'm not going to
become a religion because what's the
difference between your religion and
your religion you know you say be good
you say be good so you know why choose
one over the other and all of this is
really just like you can never know what
what truth is so I was just I was kind
of skeptical against all religions so
but when I heard this it scared me
because it made so much sense
H and I was like th how did this how did
this Escape me you know how is it that
this is making so much sense it just had
a ring of truth to it that a skeptical
mind hearing it was like whoa this is
true this is true and I'll tell you you
know when when I started
studying I was the the amount of
information I learned in about 3 months
time I
was I was totally Blown Away MH and this
is what I thought and I knew I was
learning a lot I was like I cannot
believe how much I have learned in three
months so when I would go to church I
would look at other people who had been
in the church for 10 years 20 years and
I almost would want to fall down and
worship like what must you know if
you've been in the church for a whole 10
years and I just pass out
like I'll never catch up to them I will
never because what I've learned in three
months oh man and I'm just thinking
everybody you know I'm like this thing
is so excited everybody in the church is
just like you know don't even try to
touch him man you know that's my boy
Henry over there he's been an Adventist
for 20 years don't touch him you can't
touch him you know and little did I yes
realize you were